Are you sure it was a magpie?
你确定那是喜鹊吗？
As sure as a gun
像枪一样确定
I've ordered you to stop the mission.
我已经命令你停止任务了
Why are you still following him?
你为什么还跟着他？
I don't want to give up easily.
我不想轻易放弃。
Is it because you don't want to give up easily?
是因为不想轻易放弃吗？
Do you have no other motives?
你没有其他动机吗？
At least you knew that Magpie died.
至少你知道喜鹊死了。
He didn't have the formula
他没有公式
the man from Chongqing.
来自重庆的男人。
(made a deal with Magpie to meet and exchange with him)
（与喜鹊达成协议，与他见面交流）
At Da Hua Hotel to make a deal.
到大华酒店成交。
But the Japanese followed and attacked him.
但日本人尾随并袭击了他。
Magpie ran away.
喜鹊逃跑了。
I followed Zuo Shuangtao to find the clue.
我跟着左双涛寻找线索。
And found Magpie.
并找到了喜鹊。
But it died of an accident.
但它却因意外而死亡。
And she came across Kimura Kenzo during the process.
而在这个过程中，她结识了木村贤三。
But he had no choice but to kill him.
但他别无选择，只能杀了他。
Besides, Zuo Shuangtao told me about his military identity.
另外，左双涛还跟我说了他的军人身份。
To learn from her that
向她学习
that Chongqing planned to sabotage the Border Region's economy
重庆计划破坏边区经济
to carry out a sinister plan to destroy the economy of the Border Region.
实施破坏边区经济的险恶计划。
That's what the magpie and the goose
这就是喜鹊和鹅的事
why the magpies and the geese lurk in Yan'an.
为什么喜鹊和大雁潜伏在延安。
And succeed.
并成功。
Papers for sale.
出售论文。
Sell my papers?
卖我的论文？
Selling news.
卖新闻。
Smoke and fire.
烟火。
Why are you so late?
你为什么这么晚？
There was a traffic jam.
交通堵塞了。
Where's the bicycle yesterday?
昨天的自行车在哪里？
Could it break
能不能破
after you sit there.
当你坐在那里之后。
What do you mean?
你是什​​么意思？
I didn't say you are fat.
我没说你胖啊
My bike is old.
我的自行车很旧了。
Scallion pancake.
葱油饼。
I bought it for you.
我给你买的。
No, I won't.
不，我不会。
To talk to your people?
与你的人交谈？
What's up
这是怎么回事
what's the new?
有什么新的吗？
How can you speak like my superior?
你怎么能像我的上司那样说话呢？
Of course I'm anxious.
我当然很着急。
I'm with you,
我和你在一起，
I'm really annoyed and anxious.
我实在是又气又着急。
One thing is very strange.
有件事很奇怪。
Help me analyze it.
帮我分析一下。
Alright.
好吧。
What is it?
它是什么？
Before Magpie agreed to go to the hospital yesterday,
昨天喜鹊答应去医院之前，
to make a deal with our people.
与我们的人民达成协议。
But they got exposed.
但他们却暴露了。
The deal fell through.
交易失败了。
The formula
公式
the formula should be on the magpie.
公式应该在喜鹊上。
But I didn't find it
但我没找到
then who took it?
那又是谁拿走了呢？
If he didn't have the formula,
如果他没有这个公式的话
without the formula
没有公式
I don't think he's so bold.
我不认为他有那么大胆。
But Kimura is also looking for magpies.
但木村也在寻找喜鹊。
That means they haven't got the formula either.
这意味着他们也没有得到公式。
That's right
这是正确的
that means
这意味着
after he left the trading place,
当他离开交易场所后，
and on the way to the hospital
在去医院的路上
the formula was missing
公式丢失了
I guess that
我猜可能是
that he hid the formula in his wound
他把配方藏在伤口里
when I saw the corpse,
当我看到尸体的时候
there are new stitches in the wound.
伤口上有新的缝线。
Have you analyzed it?
你分析过吗？
Please give me some time
请给我一些时间
to think it over.
想一想。
You scared me.
你吓到我了。
Why are you so interested in the formula?
你为什么对公式这么感兴趣？
Because the formula
因为公式
no matter it falls into our hands
不管它落入我们手中
or the Japanese,
或者日本人，
It will be devastating to
这将是毁灭性的
to the economy of the Chinese Communist Border Region.
对中共边区的经济。
Guoguo is disappointed with Juntong
果果对俊通很失望
with each passing day.
日趋。
And is willing to align with our ally.
并愿意与我们的盟友结盟。
We can cooperate with her in the future.
以后我们可以和她合作。
We can develop and cultivate her.
我们可以培养她、培养她。
You look so strange at me.
你看我的眼神很奇怪。
Strange?
奇怪的？
You can't see if you love me or fear me
你看不到你是爱我还是害怕我
love me or fear me?
爱我还是怕我？
Love?
爱？
You're saying that out of fear.
你这么说是出于恐惧。
See?
看？
Admit it.
承认吧。
Fear tells lies.
恐惧会说谎。
You don't love her.
你不爱她。
If I say love but I'm afraid, will you believe me?
如果我说爱但我害怕，你会相信我吗？
You don't believe me.
你不相信我。
Then how am I supposed to answer?
那我该怎么回答呢？
Women can only ask questions.
女性只能提出问题。
It's your man's business.
这是你男人的事。
Then you're being unreasonable.
那你就无理取闹了。
So please answer.
所以请回答。
Love me or fear me?
爱我还是怕我？
I'm afraid that you don't love me.
我怕你不爱我。
Just eat.
吃吧。
The car won't break down.
车不会坏。
No food.
没有食物。
Drive your car.
驾驶你的车。
It won't break down.
它不会崩溃。
News for sale!
出售消息！
Why are you so late?
你为什么这么晚？
Something bad happened.
发生了不好的事情。
What happened?
发生了什么？
Last night
昨夜
officer Kimura died on duty.
木村警官在执行任务时死亡。
What did you say
你说什么
the mourning ceremony will be held soon.
哀悼仪式即将举行。
The new chief will also come.
新任首领也将到来。
Hurry up.
赶快。
He died while doing the duty.
他在履行职责时去世了。
What a surprise!
真是一个惊喜！
It's said that the murderer who killed Kimura's chief
据说杀害木村首领的凶手是
was his informant.
是他的线人。
??? Against the wind for years ???
??? 逆风多年？？？
Once the boat capsized in the gutter,
一旦船在阴沟里翻了，
by the way, Manager Luo,
对了，罗经理，
the batch of goods
该批货物
was dispatched from Wuxi.
是从无锡发来的。
It will arrive in Shanghai in two days.
两天后将抵达上海。
Put the goods in the warehouse
将货物放入仓库
don't move for now.
暂时不要动。
Why not?
为什么不？
It's the right time to sell it at a higher price.
现在正是以更高价格出售的最佳时机。
Kimura is dead now.
木村现在死了。
Don't you know
你不知道吗
the Military Police will make trouble next.
接下来宪兵队就会制造麻烦。
We must be cautious at this time.
这个时候我们一定要小心谨慎。
Otherwise,
否则，
when did you come?
你什么时候来？
I just arrived.
我刚到。
You were so spooky.
你真是太阴森了。
I was so scared.
我很害怕。
You are so bold that you dare not breathe.
你胆大得不敢呼吸。
Stand properly.
正确站立。
The next chief will arrive soon.
下一任酋长很快就会到来。
Who's the new chief?
新任首领是谁？
Lieutenant Naoki Ueda.
上田直树中尉。
Uchida.
内田。
It's the day Miss Han Lu was caught by Zhao An.
这一天，韩露小姐被赵安抓住了。
It's Ueda that
是上田那个
who took Cold Dew away, right?
是谁带走了寒露吧？
I don't know much
我知道的不多
his background.
他的背景。
He should be with the warrior under the mountain.
他应该和山下的武者在一起。
That's right.
这是正确的。
He is Chief of Secret Service,
他是特勤局局长，
and Huang Mu Wei's hardcore bro.
还有黄慕伟的铁杆兄弟。
What's up
这是怎么回事
It's fine.
没关系。
Take it easy.
别紧张。
Captain Zhao.
Captain Zhao.
If Officer Kimura is dead,
如果木村警官死了
Is our backer gone too?
我们的靠山也走了吗？
Mumu Village is a small hill.
木木村是一座小山丘。
Plan Shan is our biggest backer.
计划山是我们最大的支持者。
Understood.
明白了。
And Huang Jinming was killed.
而黄金明也被杀了。
And Kimura wouldn't have left us alone,
木村不会丢下我们不管，
he won't spare us.
他不会放过我们的。
He managed to escape this time.
这次他成功逃脱了。
He died well.
他死得很好。
Officer.
官。
My name is Qian Chengyi.
我叫钱成义。
The rich money
有钱人有钱
to succeed.
成功。
The successful
成功者
xiucai Qian.
xiucai Qian.
Scram!
滚！
I have no interest in killing people.
我对杀人没有兴趣。
Is so cheap.
这么便宜啊。
It is too cheap.
太便宜了。
Go in.
进去。
Yes
是的
come in.
进来。
Good day, sir.
美好的一天，先生。
Officer Uchida wants me to report
内田警官要我报告
how your opium plan
你的鸦片计划如何
with your opium plan?
你的鸦片计划？
I've recently opened two more transport lines
我最近又开通了两条交通线路
to the Kuomintang-controlled area in northern Zhejiang.
到浙北国民党控制区。
The carrying capacity has doubled.
承载能力增加了一倍。
Great.
伟大的。
Please report to me directly
请直接向我汇报
directly report to me.
直接向我汇报。
Yes
是的
I thought you'd left Shanghai.
我以为你已经离开上海了
How would the Japanese know my whereabouts?
日本人怎么知道我的行踪？
I was followed by the Japanese.
跟着我的是日本人。
My plan is ruined, you know?
我的计划就泡汤了你知道吗？
So you suspect that
所以你怀疑
I betrayed you?
我背叛了你？
You asked to see me for one last time.
你要求见我最后一面。
For the last time?
最后一次？
Shoot.
射击。
Just shoot.
就开枪吧。
You must've colluded with Yamashita
你一定是和山下勾结了
to lure me out, right?
是为了引诱我出来吧？
Right
正确的
so, shoot!
所以，射击！
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Shoot!
射击！
Are you out of your mind?
你是不是疯了？
Gunshot!
枪声！
Go check it!
去检查一下吧！
Do you believe me now?
现在你相信我了吗？
You alerted the military police.
你通知了宪兵。
Follow me.
跟我来。
Someone from the mountain must have followed you.
一定是山里有人跟着你。
Why did he follow me?
他为什么跟着我？
It's not as simple as you think.
这并不像你想象的那么简单。
His investment in making films
他投资拍电影
Is just a cover.
只是一个封面而已。
The Shan Plan I came to investigate
我来调查的掸邦计划
must be related to him.
一定和他有关系。
I just want to make movies.
我只想拍电影。
I don't want to be involved in the Shan Project.
我不想参与掸邦计划。
No way.
决不。
I need to escape from that demon as soon as possible.
我需要尽快逃离那个恶魔。
You can't run away from him,
你无法逃离他
Instead, you have to go back to him.
相反，你必须回到他身边。
Why?
为什么？
Because he's using you.
因为他在利用你。
But you could also use him.
但你也可以利用他。
You want me to be
你希望我成为
and be your informant.
并成为您的线人。
Do you know what
你知道什么吗
what Yamashita did to me?
山下对我做了什么？
As long as I can succeed in this mission,
只要我能成功完成这个使命
all the credits
所有学分
for all the credit.
为了所有的功劳。
Credit?
信用？
Who's that?
那是谁？
Come with me.
跟我来。
Mr. Guo,
Mr. Guo,
I brought some clean clothes
我带了一些干净的衣服
and food for you.
和食物给你。
Who is he?
他是谁？
He's Guo Yun.
He's Guo Yun.
One night last week,
上周的一个晚上，
I just got off work
我刚下班
I was about to leave the set,
我正要离开剧组，
I heard some noise in the props warehouse.
我听到道具仓库里有一些吵闹声。
I thought the prop master was not off duty
我以为道具师没有下班
so I went to say hello.
所以我就去打招呼。
To my surprise,
出乎我的意料，
several Japanese gendarmes rushed in
几名日本宪兵冲了进来
and searched everywhere
并到处寻找
so I hid him here.
所以我把他藏在这里。
He has a special smell on him.
他身上有一种特殊的气味。
Of plate cleaning solution.
印版清洗液。
Did he tell you anything?
他有告诉你什么吗？
He can't remember anything?
他什么都不记得了？
He just said that
他只是这么说的
sunshine.
阳光。
I want to see the sun.
我想看看太阳。
I don't want to work for the Japanese anymore.
我不想再为日本人工作了。
I don't want to work for the Japanese!
我不想给日本人打工！
So you must be involved
所以你一定要参与
the Japanese's counterfeit money printing?
日本人印制假钞？
Chief Chen
陈科长
guoguo.
guoguo.
I'm back
我回来了
look at this.
看这个。
I queued for 20 minutes
我排了20分钟队
I waited in line for 20 minutes.
我排队等了20分钟。
Thank you, honey.
谢谢亲爱的。
Such a sweet talker.
真是个甜言蜜语的人。
Come on.
快点。
Try it.
尝试一下。
It's really good.
真的很棒。
Since you've been so well recently,
既然你最近过得这么好，
can you do me another favor?
你能再帮我一个忙吗？
Alright.
好吧。
What else do you want to eat?
你还想吃什么？
I'll go and buy some for you.
我去给你买一些。
I want
我想
the sewer map of Shanghai.
上海下水道地图。
You choked.
你窒息了。
Come on.
快点。
Have some soda.
喝点苏打水。
What?
什么？
That I'll drug it again?
我又要下药了？
Look at what you are doing.
看看你在做什么。
Don't
不
don't try to drag me into this.
别试图把我拖进去。
Move over.
搬过来。
We are a couple.
我们是一对。
Will you help me or not?
你会帮我还是不帮我？
I will take action.
我会采取行动。
Also,
还，
once my identity is revealed,
一旦我的身份被揭露
you can't help me
你帮不了我
you will be screwed as well.
你也会被搞砸的。
So you're helping yourself by helping me?
所以你帮助我也是在帮助你自己吗？
Are you extorting me?
你在敲诈我吗？
That's how you blackmail me.
你就是这样敲诈我的。
However, Guoguo...
However, Guoguo...
The thing you want,
你想要的东西，
to get the thing you want?
得到你想要的东西？
It's said that it's a war secret.
据说这是战争机密。
They've all transferred it from the Ministry of Industry
都是工信部调来的
to the archives of the Military Police Headquarters for safekeeping.
交宪兵司令部档案保管。
The Constitution
宪法
military Police Command?
军警司令部？
You think it's so simple
你以为这很简单
as simple as lining up for ribbon fish?
就像排队吃带鱼一样简单吗？
You're not my husband
你不是我的丈夫
my husband who manages to think quickly.
我的丈夫思维敏捷。
Next time,
下次，
just add something to the soda water
只需在苏打水中添加一些东西即可
and make me faint.
让我晕倒。
Let's eat.
我们吃饭吧。
The military has clues about the counterfeit factory.
军方掌握了有关假冒工厂的线索。
There may be an important operation in the near future.
近期可能会有重要的行动。
The time is tight.
时间很紧。
To get approval for using Juntong
获得使用骏通的批准
to get more information.
以获得更多信息。
To wipe out the counterfeit factory,
为了消灭制假工厂，
the formula and copper plates that we lost
我们丢失的配方和铜板
can be found.
可以被找寻到。
He can take part in the operation to destroy the Japanese counterfeit factory.
他可以参加摧毁日本假货工厂的行动。
But keep a close eye on the Military Commission
但要密切关注军委
Is there any other purpose in asking for the map?
索要地图还有其他目的吗？
You must be cautious.
你必须小心谨慎。
Don't expose your identity.
不要暴露你的身份。
Lu Fangfang, there's no way
卢芳芳，没办法
she's here.
她在这里。
What to drink?
喝什么？
Latte please.
请拿铁咖啡。
Hello
你好
a latte, please.
请来一杯拿铁咖啡。
All right, sir.
好吧，先生。
Have a seat.
请坐。
What about
关于什么
do you have what I asked you to bring?
我让你带的东西你带了吗？
Yes, I have.
是的，我有。
You told me
你告诉过我
you made me look like a spy.
你让我看起来像个间谍。
Great.
伟大的。
This one?
这个？
Yes, that's it!
对，就是那样！
It's against the rules
这是违反规则的
to wear it.
穿上它。
You must return it before getting off work.
您必须在下班前归还。
Got it.
知道了。
Then I'll return it to you.
然后我会把它还给你。
Why are you looking at this?
你为什么看这个？
I...
我...
My friend from Changzhou
我常州的朋友
to bid for a sewer project.
投标下水道工程。
He wants to know about
他想了解
what type of pipes
什么类型的管道
the sewer pipes in Shanghai use?
上海的下水管道用什么？
It is unexpected that all these things
没想到这一切
have become military secrets.
已成为军事机密。
That's how Japanese are.
日本人就是这样。
They even charge the price
他们甚至收取价格
you made it look like a military secret.
你让它看起来像一个军事秘密。
I need to use the bathroom.
我需要上一趟洗手间。
Alright.
好吧。
All cleaned up.
全部清理干净了。
In cooking.
在烹饪中。
I learned this before.
我以前学过这个。
You tricked me again.
你又骗我了。
How could I learn?
我怎样才能学习？
This
这
a quick response out of desperation.
出于绝望而做出的快速反应。
All are forced by your evil spirit.
一切都是被你的邪灵逼迫的。
Just like the little baby who can't swim
就像不会游泳的小宝宝一样
Into the water.
进入水中。
The water.
水。
And the same thing.
同样的事情。
Really?
真的吗？
What a surprise!
真是一个惊喜！
That he's still alive.
他还活着。
I have to kill him again.
我必须再次杀了他。
Your military commander
你的军事指挥官
you always engage in assassination.
你总是从事暗杀。
Might serve as a deterrent to others.
可能会对其他人起到威慑作用。
But the cause of national salvation
但救国事业
then
然后
these methods alone, right?
就这些方法吧？
What do you think we should do then?
你认为我们应该做什么？
You'll understand one day.
有一天你会明白的。
What you just said
你刚才说的话
I read about it in Xinhua Daily.
我在《新华日报》上看到了这件事。
Makes sense.
说得通。
Why Shangshan Hu is still alive
胡尚山为何还活着
he seems to have disappeared recently.
他最近好像失踪了。
What on earth he's doing,
他到底在做什么，
what is he discussing with Ueda?
他和上田在讨论什么？
Do you want to know
你想知道吗
what do you use it for
你用它来做什么
the sewer map?
下水道地图？
You become smarter this time.
这次你变得更聪明了。
I'll tell you then.
那我就告诉你吧。
I won't listen to your advice.
我不会听你的建议。
Please don't.
请不要。
Listen to this.
听听这个。
I have a mission tonight.
今晚我有一个任务。
You
你
stay at home.
呆在家里。
Don't run around.
别乱跑。
Ancestors,
祖先，
where do you get into trouble again?
你又在哪里惹上麻烦了？
Don't worry.
不用担心。
I just need to meet my superior.
我只需要见见我的上司。
Please warm up the quilt at home,
请大家在家把被子暖好，
wait me back
等我回来
I won't...
我不会...
Alright then.
那么好吧。
Take care of yourself.
照顾好你自己。
Director Jiang,
Director Jiang,
this is Left Shuangtao.
这是左双桃。
Last time I was in danger in Yalpei Road villa,
上次我在亚尔佩路别墅遭遇危险时，
you dressed up as a nun and saved me.
你打扮成修女救了我。
It's me.
这就是我。
Left Twin Peaches.
左双桃子。
That lurk in Taihe's trading house
潜伏在太和贸易行的
which provided us with a lot of information.
这为我们提供了很多信息。
Did you get the water pipe distribution map?
你拿到水管分布图了吗？
We got it.
我们得到了它。
Director Jiang found
姜主任发现
a printer who worked in a Japanese printing factory.
在日本印刷厂工作的印刷工。
This man's name is Guo Yun,
这个男人的名字叫郭云，
he was kidnapped by the Japanese.
他被日本人绑架了。
He had dysentery a while ago,
前段时间他得了痢疾，
the Japanese wanted to kill him,
日本人想杀了他
so they wanted to kill him.
所以他们想杀了他。
According to Guo Yun's memory,
根据郭云的记忆，
the counterfeit factory was built underground,
造假工厂建在地下，
as he didn't walk out of the ground,
因为他没有走出地面，
he walked from the factory to the sewer.
他从工厂走到下水道。
The Japanese are so cunning.
日本人真是太狡猾了。
Like a mouse,
像老鼠一样，
they are hiding in the city ground,
他们躲在城市的地下，
but no one knows where they are.
但没有人知道他们在哪里。
That Guo Yun
That Guo Yun
do you know which part of the city
你知道这个城市的哪个部分吗
where in the city you walked through the sewer?
您在城市的哪个地方走过下水道？
And the sewers are almost the same.
而且下水道也几乎是一样的。
But the only thing he remembers is that
但他唯一记得的是
he's gone for about 15 minutes.
他走了大约15分钟。
Then he saw
然后他看到
there's a sewer number
有一个下水道号码
It's 43361.
是 43361。
Is unique.
是独特的。
So we can use this to determine
所以我们可以用它来确定
where in the city
在城市的哪个地方
was located in the city?
位于城市吗？
It happened to be a rainstorm on that day.
那天正好是一场暴雨。
The water pipe was broken.
水管坏了。
The Japanese soldiers
日本士兵
were swept away by the flood.
被洪水冲走了。
Found it.
找到了。
433661.
433661。
Huxi Chaoyang Road.
Huxi Chaoyang Road.
Guo Yun said he walked for 15 minutes.
郭云说，他走了15分钟。
Guo Yun said he left for 15 minutes.
郭云说他离开了15分钟。
He started off from the underground factory.
他从地下工厂出发。
He's within 15 minutes' distance.
他距离酒店不到 15 分钟路程。
If someone is within 15 minutes' distance,
如果有人在 15 分钟的距离内，
It must be the counterfeit factory
肯定是假冒工厂
but even if it's that,
但即使是这样
the scope is still too wide.
范围还是太广了。
All we have is a clue.
我们所拥有的只是一条线索。
Who is there?
谁在那儿？
Don't.
不。
Don't shoot.
别开枪。
I'm Zuo Shuangtao's husband.
I'm Zuo Shuangtao's husband.
Why are you here?
你为什么在这？
Go back.
回去。
You're here.
你在这里。
Where can I go back?
我能回去哪里？
You won't be back?
你不会回来吗？
Director Jiang,
Director Jiang,
I can explain.
我可以解释。
I promise that
我保证
he knows nothing.
他什么都不知道。
He's too worried about me.
他太担心我了。
That's why he followed me.
这就是为什么他跟着我。
Jiaping.
Jiaping.
Come on.
快点。
Explain it.
解释一下。
Brothers,
兄弟，
I'm Zuo Shuangtao's husband.
I'm Zuo Shuangtao's husband.
I only look at my wife.
我只看着我的妻子。
Go out in the middle of the night.
半夜出去。
I was a little worried.
我有点担心。
But then I thought about it,
但后来我想了想，
I was an adult.
我已经是成年人了。
I was alone in my room.
我独自一人在我的房间里。
My head was shining green.
我的头闪着绿光。
So I followed my wife here.
于是我就跟着我的妻子来到了这里。
I didn't mean to do it.
我不是有意这么做的。
You heard
你听过
what we said just now?
我们刚才说了什么？
Just a little bit.
只是一点点。
We know
我们知道
you already knew?
你已经知道了？
You are the military...
你是军人...
You must be human.
你一定是人类。
Sorry.
对不起。
I guessed wrong.
我猜错了。
Sorry!
对不起！
You're right.
你说得对。
Director Jiang, here's the thing.
姜主任，事情是这样的。
Listen to me.
听我说。
Although he is a traitor,
虽然他是叛徒，
he must be an idle fellow.
他一定是个游手好闲的人。
He is very timid.
他很胆怯。
I promise that
我保证
he won't tell us anything.
他不会告诉我们任何事情。
If not,
如果不，
you don't have to kill him
你不必杀了他
I'll kill him myself.
我会亲自杀了他。
My wife would definitely do that.
我的妻子肯定会这么做。
You shut up.
你闭嘴。
Director Jiang,
Director Jiang,
here's the thing.
事情是这样的。
He got a lot of information for me.
他为我提供了很多信息。
He was not on our side,
他并不站在我们这边，
but
但
he made an indirect contribution.
他做出了间接贡献。
He was the one
他就是那个人
who helped me get these sewer maps.
谁帮我拿到了这些下水道地图。
How about this?
这个怎么样？
Please allow me to say something.
请允许我说几句话。
What is it?
它是什么？
Actually,
实际上，
I did hear you outside.
我在外面确实听到了你的声音。
But after analysis,
但经过分析，
still haven't found out why.
还没找到原因。
Is it convenient
方便吗
have a look.
看一看。
Let me see Guo Yun.
让我见见郭云。
Maybe I can help you find some clues.
也许我可以帮你找到一些线索。
If I help you find out any clues,
如果我能帮你找出任何线索
please let me go home.
请让我回家。
Please forgive me.
请原谅我。
I'll go home.
我会回家。
I have to warm the bed
我得暖床
and wash my wife's feet.
并给我妻子洗脚。
It seems that
看起来
you are such a good man.
你真是个好人。
Brother, look.
兄弟你看。
If you can keep me,
如果你能留住我
might be of some use.
可能有一些用处。
If you kill me,
如果你杀了我
my wife would be a widow.
我的妻子将成为寡妇。
What a shame!
真丢脸！
Although Chen Jiaping is a traitor,
陈家平虽然是汉奸，
he's innocent
他是无辜的
yes
是的
how about giving them a chance?
给他们一个机会怎么样？
Thanks.
谢谢。
I'll give you ten minutes.
我给你十分钟。
If you don't find it
如果你没有找到它
If you don't find the exact location
如果您没有找到确切位置
the exact location of the underground factory,
地下工厂的具体位置，
don't worry.
不用担心。
Have a seat.
请坐。
Just 10 minutes.
只需 10 分钟。
I'll adjust the watch
我来调整一下手表
to 11 o'clock sharp.
到11点整。
Here we go.
开始了。
Action!
行动！
Brother.
兄弟。
Take it easy.
别紧张。
Can you help me think about
你能帮我想想吗
of the day when I was kidnapped?
我被绑架的那一天？
Thank you.
谢谢。
I used to be a technician in Changxing Printing Factory.
我曾经是长兴印刷厂的一名技术员。
Six months ago,
六个月前，
on my way back from work
在我下班回来的路上
I was kidnapped by several people
我被几个人绑架了
they covered my face with a black cloth behind,
他们用黑布遮住我的脸，
and put me in the car
然后把我放进车里
how long has it been?
已经多久了？
It's a long time
很长时间了
It's about two hours.
大约有两个小时。
Maybe they made a detour on purpose.
也许他们是故意绕路的。
The car stopped.
车停了。
I was taken to a place
我被带到一个地方
It seemed to be a factory.
这似乎是一家工厂。
I heard loud machinery.
我听到机器声音很大。
After that,
在那之后，
I went to the counterfeit factory.
我去了假货工厂。
That's when they
那时他们
they took off the black cloth for me.
他们帮我把黑布脱下来。
Then try to recall
然后尝试回忆
In the counterfeit factory?
在假货工厂？
The most,
最多，
at the most,
至多，最多，
more than 40.
超过40个。
However,
然而，
new people will come from time to time
时不时会有新人来
and people will leave as well.
人们也会离开。
They said they were leaving.
他们说他们要走了。
Or she was killed.
或者她被杀了。
Those with poor skills
那些技能较差的人
and have serious illnesses.
并且患有严重的疾病。
And those who don't obey orders,
而那些不服从命令的人，
they all died.
他们都死了。
Do you know someone who works?
你认识一个工作的人吗？
No.
不。
I work with some other printers.
我与其他一些打印机合作。
We couldn't talk to each other,
我们无法互相交谈，
or ask each other's name.
或询问对方的姓名。
We call each other by numbers.
我们用号码互相称呼。
I'm No. 75.
我是75号。
Then,
然后，
did you see the other staff?
你看到其他工作人员了吗？
We have a plate-maker,
我们有制版师，
or a copper engraver.
或铜雕刻师。
We operate in different areas.
我们在不同的领域开展业务。
The Japanese forbids our contact.
日本人禁止我们接触。
We already asked you
我们已经问过你了
all the questions you asked.
你问的所有问题。
Jiaping?
Jiaping?
Why don't you change your perspective
你为什么不改变一下你的观点
and ask some details
并询问一些细节
that we haven't expected before.
这是我们之前没有预料到的。
Have you guys been to other places?
你们还去过其他地方吗？
We ate and slept there.
我们在那里吃饭、睡觉。
What do they eat then?
那他们吃什么？
Two dishes for lunch, steamed stuffed bun.
午餐两菜，包子。
And rice porridge rolls in the evening.
晚上还有稀饭卷。
One day a week
每周有一天
one day a week.
每周有一天。
Then...
然后...
Can you see out of the window?
你能看到窗外吗？
There are a few transom windows.
有几个气窗。
But all are boarded up.
但全部都用木板封起来了。
You can't see anything.
你什么也看不见。
Then...
然后...
Did you hear something outside the window?
你听到窗外有什么声音吗？
Sometimes,
有时，
It seems that I can hear
好像能听到
when I think back,
当我回想起来
It's like the sound of a ship's whistle.
就像船的汽笛声一样。
Sirens?
警报器？
Are there more in summer
夏天还有更多吗
In summer or in winter?
夏天还是冬天？
You can hear it in summer
夏天你可以听到
In winter,
冬天里，
barely.
仅仅。
And barely audible.
而且几乎听不见。
What kind of sound was that?
那是什么样的声音？
Do you still remember?
你还记得吗？
I can't learn it.
我学不会。
How about this, brother?
兄弟，这个怎么样？
You come and listen
你过来听听
I'll imitate it.
我就模仿一下
Alright?
好吧？
He is...
他是...
It's...
它是...
Help me think about it.
帮我想一下。
The number of interruptions
中断次数
and length of interruptions.
以及中断的时间长度。
Recall it carefully.
仔细回忆一下。
Let's go on.
我们继续。
And
和
I think
我认为
sounds like that.
听起来是这样的。
Are you sure that's it?
你确定是这样吗？
I am sure.
我相信。
Two long tones.
两声长音。
I've located the counterfeit factory.
我找到了假货工厂。
That's good.
那挺好的。
Ten minutes.
10分钟。
Tell me about it.
告诉我怎么回事儿。
Sir,
先生，
thank you.
谢谢。
Please leave.
请离开。
Is this how you treat him?
你就是这样对待他的吗？
Let me tell you something.
让我告诉你一件事。
With one condition.
有一个条件。
You're not qualified to negotiate terms with us.
你没有资格与我们谈判条款。
He can talk.
他会说话。
Find the counterfeit factory,
找到假冒工厂，
will you make a plan to
你会制定一个计划吗
and destroy it?
并摧毁它？
Certainly.
当然。
But before that,
但在此之前，
I need to make sure
我需要确定
you're looking for the right place.
您正在寻找正确的地方。
If we want to take action,
如果我们想采取行动，
left Pair Tao.
留下了双涛。
Will join your operation or not?
是否会加入你们的行动？
She is
她是
the best special agent.
最好的特工。
We hope she can attend it.
我们希望她能参加。
Alright.
好吧。
My term is
我的任期是
I'll take part in the operation together.
我会一起参与手术。
Why?
为什么？
Of course it's for my wife.
当然是为了我的妻子。
It's such a dangerous operation.
这是一个非常危险的操作。
To do such a dangerous operation?
要做这么危险的操作？
If my wife dies,
如果我的妻子死了
If my wife dies?
如果我的妻子死了呢？
Haven't we had enough sweet time?
我们的甜蜜时光还没有玩够吗？
And we've been working hard
而我们一直在努力
to have a son and a half daughter.
有一个儿子和一个半女儿。
We can't let your action
我们不能让你的行动
and affect our work.
并影响我们的工作。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
Didn't we agree last night?
昨晚我们不是说好了吗？
Did you really
你真的
just for Zuo Shuangtao?
just for Zuo Shuangtao?
Or what?
或者是什么？
Shouldn't a man
男人不应该吗
a man should sacrifice everything
一个人应该牺牲一切
for the woman you love?
为了你爱的女人？
Right, Director Jiang?
对吧，姜主任？
Alright.
好吧。
I promise you.
我答应你。
That's why you've taken so long to talk.
这就是为什么你花了这么长时间才说话。
Where is the counterfeit factory?
假货工厂在哪里？
Don't be anxious.
别着急。
Tell you everything.
告诉你一切。
Director Jiang
Director Jiang
has passed the serial number of the sewer
已通过下水道的序列号
and determine a range roughly, right?
并大致确定一个范围，对吗？
That is to say,
也就是说，
Chaoyang Road in Huxi
Chaoyang Road in Huxi
within 15 minutes' journey
15分钟路程内
guo Yun also mentioned that
郭云还提到
he often heard the sound of ship whistles
他经常听到船汽笛的声音
In the basement.
在地下室。
That means
这意味着
the counterfeit factory
假货工厂
along the Huangpu River,
黄浦江沿岸，
there are a lot of places near the river.
靠近河边的地方有很多。
That's right.
这是正确的。
So I asked him about it.
所以我问他这件事。
Do you hear it most in summer
夏天你听到最多的是
In summer or in winter?
夏天还是冬天？
We all know
我们都知道
wind
风
It can spread sound.
它可以传播声音。
The summer wind in Shanghai is southeast.
上海夏季风为东南风。
This proves that
这证明
the counterfeit factory
假货工厂
It's at the northwest of Huangpu River.
位于黄浦江西北岸。
Certainly,
当然，
this is not much different
这没什么不同
be the same in essentials while differing in minor points
大同小异
so I also asked
所以我也问了
what kind of sound did Guo Yun hear?
郭云听到了什么声音？
The sounds of the ships are different.
船的声音各不相同。
And the intervals
以及间隔
have different meanings.
有不同的含义。
One tone is short, it means you're coming from the starboard side of the east ship.
一声短响，说明你是从东船的右舷过来的。
Two short voices mean you'll meet from the starboard side of the east ship.
两个短促的声音意味着你们将从东船的右舷见面。
One is long
一根是长的
to leave the berth or pier.
离开泊位或码头。
The captain of two songs
两首歌的队长
for the ship
为船舶
will go through the lock.
将通过锁。
So Guo Yun heard two long tones.
于是郭云就听到了两声悠长的声音。
That means
这意味着
the counterfeit factory
假货工厂
near the ship gate of the Huangpu River.
靠近黄浦江船闸。
Jiaping.
Jiaping.
You know so much
你知道这么多
thank you, honey.
谢谢亲爱的。
Certainly.
当然。
The machines making counterfeit money.
制造假币的机器。
Would make a lot of noise.
会发出很大的噪音。
If we want to avoid detection,
如果我们想避免被发现，
and other voices to cover it up.
和其他声音来掩盖它。
I found this area
我找到了这个区域
It's a factory area,
这是一个工厂区，
so I concluded that
所以我得出的结论是
the counterfeit factory is hidden beneath this factory area.
假冒工厂就隐藏在这个厂区的下面。
This area is all factories.
这个区域全是工厂。
How can you be sure
你怎么能确定
the underground of which factory?
哪个工厂的地下？
There are many factories here,
这里有很多工厂，
those with Chinese capital
那些有中国资本的人
some are controlled by the Japanese.
有些是由日本人控制的。
However, the Japanese
然而，日本人
would choose to be built
会选择建造
In a place controlled by the Japanese.
在日本人控制的地方。
Two of these factories
其中两家工厂
are controlled by the Japanese.
都被日本人控制了。
One is a chemical factory
一是化工厂
the other's a military garment factory.
另一个是军用服装厂。
According to what Guo Yun said,
据郭云介绍，
when he passed through the factory,
当他经过工厂时
he only heard the sound of machinery.
他只听到机器的声音。
But I didn't smell the chemicals.
但我没有闻到化学物质的味道。
So I think
所以我认为
the counterfeit factory
假货工厂
there is a counterfeit
有假货
really?
真的吗？
My analysis is very accurate.
我的分析非常准确。
However,
然而，
everything you said
你所说的一切
Is only speculation
只是猜测
If the counterfeit factory is here or not.
假冒工厂是否在这里。
Before we act,
在我们行动之前，
before we act.
在我们行动之前。
Alright.
好吧。
But if Director Jiang
但如果江导
you've just agreed
你刚刚同意了
to join the operation.
加入行动。
I'm a man of my words.
我是一个言出必行的人。
However,
然而，
I have another question to ask you.
我还有一个问题要问你。
Please go ahead.
请继续。
This Japanese military clothing factory
这家日本军服工厂
how can we get in?
我们怎样才能进去？
We followed Zuo Shuangtao last night,
昨晚我们跟着左双涛，
I was told that Juntong has obtained important clues.
得知军统已经获得重要线索。
With the clue, we may destroy the counterfeit factory at one stroke.
有了线索，我们就可以一举摧毁制假工厂。
The missing formula and copper plate.
缺少配方和铜板。
Could be found.
可以找到。
He decided to take part in the raid
他决定参加突袭
In the name of protecting Zuo Shuangtao.
以保护左双涛的名义。
Due to the urgency of the situation,
由于事态紧急，
so the approval was not obtained.
所以没有获得批准。
And report it
并举报
and report to the organization after taking action.
并在采取行动后向组织报告。
Four of clubs.
四家具乐部。
That's very kind of you.
谢谢您的好意。
He asked me out for a ride.
他约我出去兜风。
It's time to relax.
是时候放松一下了。
Brother.
兄弟。
This is what I'm thinking.
这就是我的想法。
Now that Chief Kimura is dead,
现在木村队长死了
little Doudou needs a new owner.
小豆豆需要一个新主人。
But who else is qualified to ride him
但还有谁有资格骑他
who could ride Little Bean?
谁能骑小豆子？
Good point.
好点子。
Bringing a horse is different from riding.
带马与骑马不同。
Riding on the horse
骑在马上
they've got better vision
他们有更好的视力
your vision has been broadened too.
你的视野也开阔了。
The air above is fresh.
上面的空气很新鲜。
Brother.
兄弟。
Enjoy your ride.
享受你的旅程。
And take a walk.
并散步。
Alright.
好吧。
Brother.
兄弟。
That's like the Yama King,
就如阎王一样，
another Ma Zhang Fei comes.
又一个马张飞来了。
Hey.
嘿。
Brother, slow down.
兄弟你慢点
This...
这...
Brother.
兄弟。
How is it?
如何？
What about
关于什么
don't touch me.
别碰我。
I can do it myself.
我能自己做。
Myself.
我。
OK?
好的？
Slowly.
慢慢地。
I can do it myself.
我能自己做。
How is it?
如何？
Can I?
我可以吗？
The horse ridden by a Japanese
日本人骑的马
has the same urination
有相同的排尿
brother.
兄弟。
Please don't be angry.
请不要生气。
I'll talk to Little Bean later.
稍后我会和小豆子谈谈。
Just ride for a while.
就骑一会儿吧。
For real?
真正的？
And got all tangled up.
并且都陷入了纠结。
Brother.
兄弟。
Brother, don't go.
兄弟，别走。
Stand here for a while.
在这里站一会儿。
What about
关于什么
brother, wait!
兄弟，等等！
Brother.
兄弟。
Wait!
等待！
Hold on.
坚持，稍等。
It's fine.
没关系。
Go back to your work.
回去工作吧。
Brother,
兄弟，
brother!
兄弟！
You hurt Little Bean.
你伤害了小豆子。
You must apologize to it.
你必须向它道歉。
It dropped me.
它把我摔倒了。
I'll apologize to it.
我会向它道歉。
That works.
这样可行。
Then go back with me.
然后就跟我回去吧。
I'll ask Little Bean to apologize to you.
我会让小豆子向你道歉。
That's fine.
没关系。
Brother, how about this?
兄弟，这个怎么样？
Go back with me,
跟我回去吧
I apologize to both of you.
我向你们俩道歉。
No need.
不需要。
Get back to work.
回去工作。
Brother.
兄弟。
The three of us must apologize to each other.
我们三个人必须互相道歉。
Listen to me.
听我说。
Why should I apologize?
我为什么要道歉？
You're my elder brother.
你是我的哥哥。
That little bean dropped you.
那颗小豆子把你扔下了。
When you dropped you.
当你丢下你的时候。
But you made it uncomfortable again.
但你又让事情变得不舒服了。
You should apologize to it.
你应该向它道歉。
Then I caused this.
然后我就造成了这个。
And I raised Little Bean.
我抚养小豆子。
So I must apologize to both of you.
所以我必须向你们俩道歉。
You're abnormal?
你不正常吗？